Guide to the A.B. Guthrie Jr. Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- A. B. Guthrie Jr. Papers Addition, Series IX
  - Writings
    - Articles
      - "Choteau, Montana," typescript carbon, [1963?] (Box 52, Folder 614)
      - Unidentified typescript carbon pages, undated (Box 52, Folder 615)
    - Speeches
      - "Talk for Western States Tourist Director's Conference, Colorado Springs, for Life magazine." Typescript carbon, 1959 Mar 3 (Box 52, Folder 616)
  - Subject Files
    - Biographical information
      - Biographical sketches, undated (Box 52, Folder 617)
        - The Choteau Acantha, 1913 Sep 17
          See: Oversize, Box 54, folder 638
        - "Mr. and Mrs. A. B. Guthrie Jr.," Montana Parade, 1959 Jan 25
          See: Oversize, Box 54, folder 639
    - University of Kentucky Writing Workshop
      - Correspondence, publicity, lecture, syllabus, class list, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 618)
      - "Whereabouts of work" (list of Guthrie submissions), typescript carbon, undated (Box 52, Folder 619)
  - Printed Material with contributions by Guthrie
    - The American Scholar 31: 4 Review of Letters of the Lewis and Clark Expedition and Related Documents, ed. by Donald Jackson, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 620)
    - Argosy 336:2 "The Stomper," 40, 62-65, 1953 Feb (Box 52, Folder 621)
    - Esquire 28:4 "Bargain at Moon Dance," 72, undated
    - Frontier and Midland 15:3 "Indian Burial," poem, 227, 1935 (Box 52, Folder 622)
    - Frontier Town [amusement park brochure] "One Man's Folly," 1-3, 1950 (Box 52, Folder 623)
    - Liberty, "Old Mother Hubbard," 34, 1946 May 11 (Box 52, Folder 624)
    - Nieman Reports 12:1 "DeVoto - A Memoir," 3-6, 1958 Jan (Box 52, Folder 625)
    - Nieman Reports 12:2 "Guthrie Blasts Charges By Legion's Committee," 18, 1958 Apr (Box 52, Folder 626)
    - The Reporter 27:9 "I Know Where I Am From," 50-52, 1962 Nov 22 (Box 52, Folder 627)
    - The Writer 62:11 "Characters and Compassion," 359-362, 1949 Nov (Box 52, Folder 628)
  - Works by others
    - American Pioneer Trails Association Publications
      - Garnet M. and Herbert O. Brayer, "American Cattle Trails, 1500-1900." Bayside, New York. With: map, 1952 (Box 52, Folder 628a)
      - Howard R. Driggs, "Mormon Trail: Pathway of Pioneers Who Made Deserts Blossom." Manchester. With: map, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 628b)
      - Robert H. Fletcher, "American Adventure: Story of the Lewis and Clark Expedition." Manchester., 1945 (Box 52, Folder 628c)
      - Walter Meacham, "Old Oregon Trail, Roadway of American Home Builders." Manchester. With: map, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 628)
      - Stanley Vestal, "Wagons Southwest: Story of Old Trail to Santa Fe." Manchester. With: map, 1946 (Box 52, Folder 628e)
    - Dorothy Pye Barrett, "Montana Glimpses," inscribed to A. B. Guthrie Jr. Great Falls, Montana, undated (Box 52, Folder 629)
    - "Catalogue 48: Old, New & Rare Books on the American West...Featuring More Books from the Library of A. B. Guthrie Jr. Jack D. Rittenhouse, Bookseller", [ca. 1980] (Box 52, Folder 630)
    - Bernard DeVoto, Commencement Address at Colorado University, Special Centennial Supplement to the Silver and Gold Record, 1976
      See: Oversize, Box 54, folder 641
    - W. D. Funkhouser, "The Ethnology Behind the War," inscribed to A. B. Guthrie Jr. (Box 53, Folder 631)
    - "Hoofprints from the Yellowstone Corral of the Westerners," 3:2, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 632)
    - Dayton Kohler, "A. B. Guthrie Jr. and the West," English Journal 40:2, 1951 Feb (Box 53, Folder 633)
    - "The Log Cabin Studio of Charles M. Russell", [ca. 1934] (Box 53, Folder 634)
    - Donald Stevens, "The Trout," The Frontier, 8, 1921 May (Box 53, Folder 635)
    - Walter Prescott Webb, Review of Bernard DeVoto's The Course of Empire, Saturday Review, 22, 1952 Nov 22 (Box 53, Folder 636)
    - Kathryn Wright, "Billings: The Magic City and How it Grew," inscribed to A. B. Guthrie, 1961., undated (Box 53, Folder 637)
- Oversize
  - The Choteau Acantha, 1913 Sep 17 (Box 54, Folder 638)
  - "Mr. and Mrs. A. B. Guthrie Jr.," Montana Parade, 1959 Jan 25 (Box 54, Folder 639)
  - Esquire 28:4 "Bargain at Moon Dance," 72., undated (Box 54, Folder 640)
  - Bernard DeVoto, Commencement Address at Colorado University, Special Centennial Supplement to the Silver and Gold Record, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 641)